A Guide to the Legal Papers of James Fenimore Cooper, 1832-1859
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Legal Papers of James Fenimore Cooper, 1832-1859
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6245-l
This collection consists of 12 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This item was purchased from John E. Fleming on 15 January 1965.
Scope and Content Information
Papers of James Fenimore Cooper, including legal documents with notes regarding Cooper's libel case against James Watson Webb, book reviews, and letters, including letters written by Susan F. Cooper.
Contents List
- Letter from James Fenimore Cooper to Peter A. Jay 17 October 1832, ALS, with handwritten copy (5 pages), 3 pages.
  James Fenimore Cooper to Peter A. Hay, regarding cholera, family affairs, financial affairs with Carey & Lea, wines. Mentions Headsman, St. Bernards.
  This is not found in James Franklin Beard's Letters and Journals of James Fenimore Cooper.
- Document of lawsuit against James Watson Webb 19 June 1839, D, 4 pages.
  Document relating to Cooper's lawsuit against James Watson Webb, editor of The Morning Courie r and New York Enquirer.
- Book Reviews by James Fenimore Cooper 29 August, 5 September 1840, Newspaper Clippings
  Review of Homeward Bound and Home as Found: a Sequel to Homeward Bound by James F. Cooper. Clipped from The New World.
- Indictments and affadavits brought against James Watson Webb 10 October 1840, Ds, 15 pages
  Indictment and affadavits brought against James Watson Webb, editor of The Morning Courier and New York Enquirer, by James F. Cooper.
- Letter from S. [Cuffin?] to James Watson Webb 26 December 1842, ALS, 1 page.
  S. [Cuffin?] to James Watson Webb [concerning Cooper's Libel suit against Webb].
- Letter from Susan F. Cooper to Mr. Jay 2 September 1850, ALS, 3 pages
- Letter from Susan F. Cooper to Miss Jay 26 October 1851, ALS, 4 pages
- Letter from Susan F. Cooper to Mrs. Banyer 26 January 1855, ALS, 3 pages
- Letter from Susan F. Cooper to Mr. Jay 16 June 1859, ALS, 4 pages
- Notes regarding Cooper's libel case n.d., Ms, 17 pages
  Notes regarding Cooper's libel case against James Watson Webb [ Homeward Bound and Home As Found].
- Notes on cooper's Libel case against James Watson Webb n.d., Ms, in pencil, 4 pages
- Notes on a lawsuit between Turner and Prentiss n.d., Ms, 2 pages
  Notes on a lawsuit between Turner and Prentiss, probably made in connection with one of Cooper's libel suits.